RANJU RAVEENDRAN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Auckland, New Zealand 02102467215 ranjurave@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ranjurave www.github.com/ranjurave www.ranjurave.com

CICD

Unity

REST API

Unreal Engine

Over the past years, I have worked in a range of areas, including Web Development, Game Development, XR Development, and Computer Graphics. Have a degree in Computer Science and completed an Advanced Software Developer course and a Master's in Creative Technologies. Throughout my career, I have consistently demonstrated my ability to quickly grasp new technologies and perform effectively even under pressure. My areas of expertise are Full Stack Development, Game & App Development and 3D Graphics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C++ HTML
C# CSS
Python JavaScript
.NET Node.js

SQL Server React Adobe Creative Suit

MongoDB Git Maya

EXPERIENCES

Yoobee College, Auckland

Software Engineering Lecturer

February 2018 to Present

Deliver courses to year 2 and year 3 students of Bachelor of Software Engineering.

- Design and deliver courses to NZQA standards
- Coach and guide final-year students in completing Web and Game Development projects.
- Delivering the following courses:
 - Web app development in Python and Flask
 - Programming C# and C++
 - Game development using Unreal Engine and Unity
 - o 3D Content Creation

Niramsoft

Freelance Software Developer

July 2021 to Present

- Develop Web Applications
- Develop Mobile AR Applications
- Develop Game Prototypes

Native Software, Tauranga

Software Developer Intern

October 2022 to December 2022.

- Worked with React, C#, SQL and .NET
- Developed a Web API for a bespoke ticket-tracking system
- Connected APIs from different ticketing systems to the backend

Achievement: Completed all features using the .NET framework as per the software specification document with no assistance from the mentors and manager.

Huhu Studios, Snells Beach, Auckland

Senior Animator / Generalist

September 2010 to January 2018

- Performed scripting in Maya Embedded Library (MEL)
- Created 3D models in Maya
- Rigged character and prop models for animation
- Performed scene layout and set dressing
- Created 3D animations

Achievement: Started as a junior animator and progressed to become a senior animator. Assisted other departments, including modelling and rigging, during periods of staff shortage.

EDUCATION

Advanced Software Developer (Level 6 NZQA) – Oct to Dec 2022 Software Developer - AI & Cloud (Level 5) – Aug to Sep 2022 Full Stack Developer (Level 4) – May to July 2022

Mission Ready HQ, Auckland

Master of Creative Technologies (Honours) - 2020 - 2021

Auckland University of Technology, Auckland

Bachelor of Computer Science - 1998 - 2001

AJ College of Science and Technology, Kerala University, India

SOFT SKILLS

Communication - written and verbal Research

Team Player Analytical Skills
Fast Learner Problem Solving
Team Management Attention to Detail

REFERENCES

References can be provided on request.